<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Lasseigne Lab</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Lasseigne Lab</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Education</title>
      <link>/education/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/education/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to our data science education page. If you are UAB trainees, faculty, or staff and want to get started, please check out these resources.  Information about the Lasseigne Lab-hosted &amp;lsquo;Data Science Office Hours&amp;rsquo; can be found in this guide The Lasseigne Lab executes most downstream omics analysis with R in RStudio and we generally recommend the same for others. Directions for downloading and installing R and RStudio, as well as vetted R programming lessons for beginners, can be found here</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Website!</title>
      <link>/blog/new-website/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/new-website/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to the new Lasseigne Lab website! While still under construction, we wanted to share a first post about our new team!
(left to right) Tabea Soelter, Jen Fisher, and Jordan Whitlock
We&amp;rsquo;ve been fortunate to recruit such a strong, interdisciplinary team. This past summer we welcomed Sasha Thalluri and Avery Williams, two undergraduate genetics research assistants enthusiastic to learn more about science and the lab environment. Shortly after, Randi Wood joined as a staff scientist and our lab manager.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BioTrain Computational Biology Workshop 2018</title>
      <link>/2018-06-04-biotraincompbioworkshop2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018-06-04-biotraincompbioworkshop2018/</guid>
      <description>Objective/Rationale: This one day workshop is intended to provide HudsonAlpha undergraduate student BioTrain interns and graduate rotation students an introduction to computational biology through a discussion on why computers are necessary in genomics, short unix shell and R tutorials followed by hands-on exercises (The Carpentries lessons), and tips on how to ask for help, keeping a computational lab notebook, and finding additional learning resources. Pre-requisites: Curiosity about computational biology and a basic understanding of the concepts of files and directories.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brittany Lasseigne&#39;s Teaching and Outreach</title>
      <link>/brittany-education/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/brittany-education/</guid>
      <description>Guest speaker for MCBIOS19 Student Career Development Session; &amp;lsquo;Social Media for Science Careers&amp;rsquo; slides
 Guest speaker for HudsonAlpha GTAC: Advanced Concepts workshop; &amp;lsquo;Introduction to Machine Learning with Genomic Data Applications&amp;rsquo; slides
 Content Developer and instructor for the 2018 HudsonAlpha BioTrain Computational Biology Bootcamp (4 June 2018)
 Co-lead instructor of a Software Carpentry Workshop at the George Washington University in Washington D.C. (8-9 March 2018) on Unix shell, Git version control, and R programming.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact Us</title>
      <link>/contact-us/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/contact-us/</guid>
      <description> The Lasseigne Lab is in the Cell, Developmental and Integrative Biology Department at The University of Alabama at Birmingham School of Medicine. Our lab is located on the 9th floor of Tinsley Harrison Tower in 960.
 Contact PI Dr. Brittany Lasseigne at bnp0001@uab.edu </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publications</title>
      <link>/publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/</guid>
      <description> Brittany Lasseigne Vishal Oza Drew Hardigan Tabea Soelter </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research</title>
      <link>/research/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/research/</guid>
      <description>ul { list-style-type: none; margin: 0; padding: 0; overflow: hidden; }
li { float: left; }
li a { display: block; color: white; text-align: center; padding: 16px; text-decoration: none; }
li a:hover { background-color: #FFFFFF; }    
 Biomarker discovery in kidney cancer Discovery of kidney cancer diagnostic biomarkers and therapeutic signatures
    ___________________________________________________________________________________________  Causal variant identification in neurodegenerative disease Identification of causal variants and genes in neurodegenerative disease</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>