<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Lasseigne Lab</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Lasseigne Lab</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>New Website!</title>
      <link>/blog/new-website/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/new-website/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to the new Lasseigne Lab website! While still under construction, we wanted to share a first post about our new team!
(left to right) Tabea Soelter, Jen Fisher, and Jordan Whitlock
We&amp;rsquo;ve been fortunate to recruit such a strong, interdisciplinary team. This past summer we welcomed Sasha Thalluri and Avery Williams, two undergraduate genetics research assistants enthusiastic to learn more about science and the lab environment. Shortly after, Randi Wood joined as a staff scientist and our lab manager.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Integrative analysis of genomic data in complex disease</title>
      <link>/research-projects/integrative-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/research-projects/integrative-analysis/</guid>
      <description>As a postdoctoral fellow, Brittany lead and/or participated in several projects aimed at understanding the mechanisms behind broad molecular changes (e.g., thousands of differentially expressed genes between normal and disease tissues). For example, she and her colleagues identified transcription factor binding sites with altered DNAm in prostate cancer and genomic regulation of triple negative breast cancer invasion. Likewise, by measuring relative cell proliferation from gene expression data across 19 cancers, they demonstrated cell proliferation is a major driver of gene expression variation, is strongly associated with clinical characteristics, and by stratifying on cell proliferation, improved predictive models of patient survival.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Causal variant identification in neurodegenerative disease</title>
      <link>/research-projects/pathogenic-variant-discovery/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/research-projects/pathogenic-variant-discovery/</guid>
      <description>Brittany&amp;rsquo;s first postdoc project was a highly collaborative effort with Drs. Rick Myers and Greg Cooper (HudsonAlpha), Liz Cirulli (Duke), David Goldstein (Columbia), and Biogen Idec to sequence almost 3,000 amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) patient exomes to identify new genes contributing to ALS risk. They confirmed several known ALS genes and identified TBK1 as a novel ALS gene, revealing a key role of the autophagic pathway in ALS etiology and suggesting specific targets for therapeutic intervention.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Biomarker discovery in kidney cancer</title>
      <link>/research-projects/biomarkers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/research-projects/biomarkers/</guid>
      <description>A key motivator of our lab&amp;rsquo;s research is applying genomics to complex diseases with the goal of discovering clinically relevant signatures that might be used to improve patient care. In graduate school, Brittany led a project applying next-generation sequencing technologies to kidney cancer tumor and normal tissues to assess DNA methylation, copy number variation, and microsatellite instability associated with kidney cancer etiology and progression. This project was a collaboration with Drs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Computational Tools</title>
      <link>/research-projects/tool-development/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/research-projects/tool-development/</guid>
      <description>Building on the lab&amp;rsquo;s interest in sharing tools with the research community, we are developing project-relevant R packages and Shiny applications including test data and instructional vignettes to facilitate exploration, visualization, and analysis of multidimensional data sets. Such tools will accelerate future discoveries by allowing more rapid analysis of the relationships among genomic data sets and with disease, as well as increase research reproducibility in data-driven approaches to complex disease research.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact Us</title>
      <link>/contact-us/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/contact-us/</guid>
      <description> The Lasseigne Lab is in the Cell, Developmental and Integrative Biology Department at The University of Alabama at Birmingham School of Medicine. Our lab is located on the 9th floor of Tinsley Harrison Tower in 960.
 Contact PI Dr. Brittany Lasseigne at bnp0001@uab.edu </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Education</title>
      <link>/education/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/education/</guid>
      <description>Lasseigne Lab Hosted Data Science Office Hours for UAB trainees, faculty, and staff Data Science Guides:  R Master Guide RNA-Seq Guide  Brittany Lasseigne&amp;rsquo;s Recent Teaching and Science Outreach  Guest speaker for MCBIOS19 Student Career Development Session; &amp;lsquo;Social Media for Science Careers&amp;rsquo; slides
 Guest speaker for HudsonAlpha GTAC: Advanced Concepts workshop; &amp;lsquo;Introduction to Machine Learning with Genomic Data Applications&amp;rsquo; slides
 Content Developer and instructor for the 2018 HudsonAlpha BioTrain Computational Biology Bootcamp (4 June 2018)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publications</title>
      <link>/publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/</guid>
      <description> Click here for Brittany Lasseigne&amp;rsquo;s Publications Click here for Vishal Oza&amp;rsquo;s Publications Click here for Drew Hardigan&amp;rsquo;s Publications </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research</title>
      <link>/research/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/research/</guid>
      <description>ul { list-style-type: none; margin: 0; padding: 0; overflow: hidden; }
li { float: left; }
li a { display: block; color: white; text-align: center; padding: 16px; text-decoration: none; }
li a:hover { background-color: #FFFFFF; }    
 Biomarker discovery in kidney cancer Discovery of kidney cancer diagnostic biomarkers and therapeutic signatures
    ___________________________________________________________________________________________  Causal variant identification in neurodegenerative disease Identification of causal variants and genes in neurodegenerative disease</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>