<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>machine-learning on Lasseigne Lab</title>
    <link>/tags/machine-learning/</link>
    <description>Recent content in machine-learning on Lasseigne Lab</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 22 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/machine-learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Integrative analysis of genomic data in complex disease</title>
      <link>/research-projects/integrative-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/research-projects/integrative-analysis/</guid>
      <description>As a postdoctoral fellow, Brittany lead and/or participated in several projects aimed at understanding the mechanisms behind broad molecular changes (e.g., thousands of differentially expressed genes between normal and disease tissues). For example, she and her colleagues identified transcription factor binding sites with altered DNAm in prostate cancer and genomic regulation of triple negative breast cancer invasion. Likewise, by measuring relative cell proliferation from gene expression data across 19 cancers, they demonstrated cell proliferation is a major driver of gene expression variation, is strongly associated with clinical characteristics, and by stratifying on cell proliferation, improved predictive models of patient survival.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Biomarker discovery in kidney cancer</title>
      <link>/research-projects/biomarkers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/research-projects/biomarkers/</guid>
      <description>A key motivator of our lab&amp;rsquo;s research is applying genomics to complex diseases with the goal of discovering clinically relevant signatures that might be used to improve patient care. In graduate school, Brittany led a project applying next-generation sequencing technologies to kidney cancer tumor and normal tissues to assess DNA methylation, copy number variation, and microsatellite instability associated with kidney cancer etiology and progression. This project was a collaboration with Drs.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>