<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog on Lasseigne Lab</title>
    <link>https://lasseigne.org/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog on Lasseigne Lab</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 16 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://lasseigne.org/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>10 Simple Rules</title>
      <link>https://lasseigne.org/blog/10-simple-rules/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lasseigne.org/blog/10-simple-rules/</guid>
      <description>Ten simple rules for using public biological data for your research
Journal: PLoS Computational Biology
Authors: Vishal H. Oza, Jordan H. Whitlock, Elizabeth J. Wilk, Angelina Uno-Antonison, Brandon Wilk, Manavalan Gajapathy, Timothy C. Howton, Austyn Trull, Lara Ianov, Elizabeth A. Worthey, and Brittany N. Lasseigne
With an increasing amount of biological data available publicly, there is a need for a guide on how to successfully download and use this data. The 10 simple rules for using public biological data are: (1) use public data purposefully in your research; (2) evaluate data for your use case; (3) check data reuse requirements and embargoes; (4) be aware of ethics for data reuse; (5) plan for data storage and compute requirements; (6) know what you are downloading; (7) download programmatically and verify integrity; (8) properly cite data; (9) make reprocessed data and models Findable, Accessible, Interoperable, and Reusable (FAIR) and share; and (10) make pipelines and code FAIR and share.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2022 Preprints</title>
      <link>https://lasseigne.org/blog/2022-preprints/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lasseigne.org/blog/2022-preprints/</guid>
      <description>CINmetrics: An R package for chromosomal instability analysis
Authors: Vishal H. Orza, Jennifer L. Fisher, Roshan Darjoi, Brittany N. Lasseigne
Genomic instability is an important hallmark of cancer and more recently has been identified in others like neurodegenrative diseases. Chromosomal instability, as a measure of genomic instability, has been used to characterize clinical and biological phenotypes associated with these diseases by measuring structural and numerical chromosomal alterations. There have been multiple chromosomal instability scores developed across many studies in the literature; however, these scores have not been compared because of the lack of a single tool available to calculate and facilitate these various metrics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2022 Publications</title>
      <link>https://lasseigne.org/blog/2022-publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lasseigne.org/blog/2022-publications/</guid>
      <description>Liquid biopsies in epilepsy: biomarkers for etiology, diagnosis, prognosis, and therapeutics
Journal: Human Cell
Authors: Jordan H. Whitlock, Tabea M. Soelter, Avery S. Williams, Andrew A. Hardigan, and Brittany N. Lasseigne
Epilepsy is one of the most common diseases of the central nervous system, impacting nearly 50 million people around the world. Heterogeneous in nature, epilepsy presents in children and adults alike. Currently, surgery is one treatment approach that can completely cure epilepsy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2021 Publications</title>
      <link>https://lasseigne.org/blog/2021-publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lasseigne.org/blog/2021-publications/</guid>
      <description>A role for GLUT3 in glioblastoma cell invasion that is not recapitulated by GLUT1
Journal: Cell Adhesion &amp;amp; Migration
Authors: Catherine J Libby, Sajina Gc, Gloria A. Benavides, Jennifer L. Fisher, Sarah E. Williford, Sixue Zhang, Anh Nhat Tran, Emily R. Gordon, Amber B. Jones, Kaysaw Tuy, William Flavahan, Juan Gordillo, Ashlee Long, Sara J. Cooper, Brittany N. Lasseigne, Corinne E. Augelli-Szafran, Victor Darley-Usmar, and Anita B. Hjelmeland
The multifaceted roles of metabolism in invasion have been investigated across many cancers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Second Update</title>
      <link>https://lasseigne.org/blog/second-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lasseigne.org/blog/second-update/</guid>
      <description>We are back with another update! Thank you for taking the time to check in on how our lab is evolving and growing! It has been almost two years since our last update, so a lot has happened!
To begin, here&amp;rsquo;s a little &amp;ldquo;lab space update&amp;rdquo; on how we&amp;rsquo;ve made ourselves at home in our dry lab space: We are so thankful for this space to hold our ever-growing lab! Next, we&amp;rsquo;d like to introduce you to our newer members and summer students that we have had since the last update:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First Update</title>
      <link>https://lasseigne.org/blog/first-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lasseigne.org/blog/first-update/</guid>
      <description>It has been an eventful eight months. Our first and most recent entry was posted in March of this year, and much has happened since then! While COVID-19 has had a tragic negative effect on the world around us, we have been very fortunate to have had plenty of positive events as well.
Since our last update, Drew has moved on to a neurosurgery residency at Duke University. Randi has also moved on to opportunities elsewhere.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Website!</title>
      <link>https://lasseigne.org/blog/new-website/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lasseigne.org/blog/new-website/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to the new Lasseigne Lab website! While still under construction, we wanted to share a first post about our new team!
**(left to right) Tabea Soelter, Jen Fisher, and Jordan Whitlock** We&amp;rsquo;ve been fortunate to recruit such a strong, interdisciplinary team. This past summer we welcomed Sasha Thalluri and Avery Williams, two undergraduate genetics research assistants enthusiastic to learn more about science and the lab environment. Shortly after, Randi Wood joined as a staff scientist and our lab manager.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
