<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>website on Lasseigne Lab</title>
    <link>/categories/website/</link>
    <description>Recent content in website on Lasseigne Lab</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/website/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Second Update</title>
      <link>/blog/second-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/second-update/</guid>
      <description>We are back with another update! Thank you for taking the time to check in on how our lab is evolving and growing! It has been almost two years since our last update, so a lot has happened!
To begin, here&amp;rsquo;s a little &amp;ldquo;lab space update&amp;rdquo; on how we&amp;rsquo;ve made ourselves at home in our dry lab space: We are so thankful for this space to hold our ever-growing lab! Next, we&amp;rsquo;d like to introduce you to our newer members and summer students that we have had since the last update:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First Update</title>
      <link>/blog/first-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/first-update/</guid>
      <description>It has been an eventful eight months. Our first and most recent entry was posted in March of this year, and much has happened since then! While COVID-19 has had a tragic negative effect on the world around us, we have been very fortunate to have had plenty of positive events as well.
Since our last update, Drew has moved on to a neurosurgery residency at Duke University. Randi has also moved on to opportunities elsewhere.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Website!</title>
      <link>/blog/new-website/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/new-website/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to the new Lasseigne Lab website! While still under construction, we wanted to share a first post about our new team!
We&amp;rsquo;ve been fortunate to recruit such a strong, interdisciplinary team. This past summer we welcomed Sasha Thalluri and Avery Williams, two undergraduate genetics research assistants enthusiastic to learn more about science and the lab environment. Shortly after, Randi Wood joined as a staff scientist and our lab manager. Randi has been as been working hard to build the wet side of the lab.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
